ANDRES CHOQUE

andreschoque71@gmail.com • LinkedIn • Github

SUMMARY

Recent Computer Science graduate with a passion for technology, business, travel, and leadership. Experienced in software development through Samaritan's Purse, CREOTEC, and Liberty University, by building web applications and websites using a MERN stack that provide value to many clients. Experienced in international travel through adapting in different cultural environments such as the Middle East, South America, and North America. Profficient in Spanish and English Communication. Career is supported by a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science and multiple Software Engineering internships.

SKILLS

- Languages: English and Spanish with Bilingual Profficiency
- Code: Javascript, TypeScript, React, Angular, Node, Express, HTML, CSS, C#, Python, MATLAB
- Tools: Git, Github, Bitbucket, SQL, MongoDB, Postman, Powershell, Azure, Pytorch

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Intern | Samaritan's Purse

May 2022 — Aug 2022

- Developed 4 user interface features using Angular that allow users to choose donation types
- Integrated 2 back-end features using C# that performs API calls to the database to retrieve data and improve effectiveness by 15 seconds
- Automated a drag-and-drop feature using Typescript effectively increasing functionality by 10%

Competitor/Researcher | OpenCV & Microsoft

Mar 2021 — Aug 2021

- Constructed and researched a drone model that detects malicious plants, and develop effective crop yields
- Developed a crop row alignment system using Computer Vison and Python to simplify data collection by 30%
- Implemented a Hough Line Algorithm using Pythorch and Python to maximize region identification

Software Engineer Intern | CREOTEC

May 2021 — July 2021

- Led a team of 4 interns to develop a website using PHP & WordPress to sell items for 1000 clients
- Translated spanish business needs into a functional English app increasing efficiency by 25%
- Integrated forms using PHP to allow users to choose payment plans and browse different prosthetics to purchase

EDUCATION

Liberty University | Bachelors of Science in Computer Science

Aug 2019 — May 2023

- Honors: Magna Cum Laude, Dean's List
- Extra Curriculars: Open CV Al Competition 2021, Student Government Association Senator
- Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Computer Architecture, Theory of Programming Languages, Operating Systems

PROJECTS

Web App | Center for Financial Literacy

Aug 2022 — May 2023

- Led a team of 5 senior computer science capstone students to develop a web application
- Engineered a user interface using React to help 2000 students visualize and budget their finances
- Developed back end code using NodeJS that connects to MongoDB using APIs that retrives student's input

ACHIEVEMENTS

Phase 1 Finalist OpenCV AI Competition
National Youth Science Camp Bolivian Delegate
Gold Medalist for Robotics Competition

2021

2018

2015 & 2016